# MAXWELL COOPER

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER







+1 (443) 841 5751 maxwellcharlescooper@gmail.com maxwellcharlescooper.github.io/ Prooklyn



# **PROFILE**

Software engineer with particular experience in frontend technologies, specifically using Typescript to build React web apps for early-stage startups. Special emphasis on UI/UX design/execution, as well as general app management including DevOps and bug fixing.

# **EDUCATION**

## **BROWN UNIVERSITY**

2014-2018

Electrical Engineering, Sc.B.

GPA: 3.4

## HEREFORD HIGH SCHOOL

2010-2014

GPA: 4.0

## **TOWSON UNIVERSITY**

2013

Multivariable Calculus (MATH275)

GPA: 4.0

## **SKILLS**

## **TECHNICAL**

React, TypeScript, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, Python, Java

## **PROFESSIONAL**

Git, Jira, VS Code, AWS products (EC2, CloudFront, RDS, Lambda, CodePipeline, CloudWatch), Agile (Scrum), TEFL

## **TESTS**

SAT: 2340 ACT: 34

SAT II: Chem 800, Math II 800,

Physics 780

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **INFONDRIAN**

Software Engineer, January 2020-Present

- Built entire frontend SPA for a cloud-based radiation oncology chartchecking software startup from start to finish using React Typescript (including custom hooks) and asynchronous API calls/different custom features, along with many different imported libraries such as styledcomponents, Axios, react-router-dom, D3.js, momentJS, socket.io, jscookie, Recharts, qs, react-toastify, react-datepicker, Material UI, etc.
- Completed backend work (running on NodeJS and TypeScript) including writing Postman API tests, debugging 500 internal server errors, SQL queries (Sequelize) to the database, writing GET functions from the API route to the response and Lambda functions on a separate repository that execute on the database itself.
- Architected entire frontend CI/CD pipeline with GitHub trigger from dev to prod including testing stage using AWS CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, as well as DNS networking using AWS Route 53 and AWS Cloudfront to point to an S3 bucket.
- Used various Docker containers including running a local PostgreSQL database, an Nginx proxy for a secondary API, frontend testing using Docker containers running CodeceptJS and Chrome.
- Set up authentication for React app using Auth0 and later transitioning to a custom login page with Amazon Cognito.

#### **INTUS CARE**

Frontend Software Engineer, October 2019-January 2020

- One of two software engineers to develop the frontend of a caregiver management application for a Brown startup company, a finalist of the Brown Venture Prize and 2019 MassChallenge winner.
- Used React Native with TypeScript, MongoDB/Azure for the database/ server.

## **OTHER**

#### GOTOCO TEFL VOLUNTEER PROGRAM

Summer 2019 - Beijing, China

• Taught English to adult Chinese students while earning TEFL.

#### COLLEGE CRUSADES FTC STUDENT ADVISOR

2018-2019 - Providence, RI

• Mentored at-risk high school students in robotics competition.